Lionel Kubwimana

Software Engineer

I am a self-taught Software Engineer with a background of a Network Engineer and 2 years of work experience. I have a passion for writing code to solve (only) real-world problems through challenging projects. Seeking new opportunities in Budapest.



lionel.kubwimana@gmail.com

+33 6 15 44 29 22

www.linkedin.com/in/l-kubwimana



www.github.com/LionelKb

Work Experience

09/2014 - Present Paris, France

Network Engineer

Covage

Telco operator specialized in fiber deployment and IP services.

- Testing, validating and writing technical documentation describing new IP services and solutions to be deployed on the MPLS/FTTH Covage network.
- Product Owner of two in-house projects involving the automation of the network. Responsible of the code, strategy, vision, roadmap and feature
- Level 3 Support Escalation for the Network Operation Center team.

01/2014 - 06/2014 Paris, France

Network Engineer Intern

Covage

Tasks/Achievements

- Built Command Line (CLI) tools in a Linux environment.
- Automated the management of the network configurations to be used for a specific customer request. The tool developed generate the needful configurations files for the routers, the switches and the CPEs.
- Built a network configuration audit tool. It checks the incoherences due to manual provisionning of the existing services.
- Studied the needed steps for a migration from Per-Vlan Spanning-Tree to Multiple Spanning-Tree on a part of the aggregation network.

07/2012 - 12/2012 Paris, France

Software Engineer Intern

Covage

Tasks/Achievements

- Built web-based tools running in a Linux-Apache-MySQL-PHP environment.
- Designed a tool used for scheduled planned works on the fibers to identify and inform the customers affected by the fiber cut. It improved the existing process from one working day to 30 minutes.
- Developed an user-friendly interface giving the outline of parts of the network using the Google Maps API and queries to a GIS database containing the entire Covage fiber network.
- Automated the CPE turn-up deployed on the entire network using a DHCP server with a embeded database and an single web page used to register the new equipments to be delivered.

Education

05/2016 - Present

Full Stack Web Development Certification

Free Code Camp

09/2011 - 06/2014

Network Engineer's degree Université de Technologie de Troyes Troyes, France

Online Course

Coding Skills

1	1	1
Perl		
Linux		
PHP		
MySQL		
HTML/CSS		
Javascript		
Python		

Projects

Automated Network Service Provisioning

 Web-based platform used by the delivery team to configure and provision a service without any access to the CLI of the network equipments.

Network Configuration Audit

 Perl scripts that check if the configuration of the network equipments is done according to the specifications described by the engineering team.

Soft Skills

Interpersonal Relationships

Intercultural and interreligious awareness and openness aiming for a more united world.

Group Leading

Guiding teenagers to make life decisions and embrace perspectives that build a more fraternal world.

Languages

Enalish

Full professional proficiency

French

Native or Bilingual

Italian

Elementary proficiency

Native or Bilingual

Interests

Reading (Inspirational books) | Music (Guitar) | Travelling | Hungarian language & culture